Akshaya Sreenivasan

CONTACT

aks.auburn@gmail.com | 0401542615 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/aks-sreenivasan/ | https://github.com/aksCo

PROFILE

2.5 years of experience as a management and technical consultant for clients in financial services (insurance and banking), 1 year of experience as a lean six sigma project leader and 1 year working on programming projects utilising MATLAB and MERN stack.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Industrial and Systems Engineering Auburn University | Aug 2017 | Auburn, AL, USA | Accredited by Engineers' Australia

CERTIFICATIONS

USYD - Full-Stack Development Boot Camp | Nov 2020 - May 2021 | Sydney, NSW IASSC - Green Belt in Lean Six Sigma | May 2018

KEY SKILLS

- Data analytics and statistical analysis (Excel, VBA, R, Minitab, SQL)
- Programming skills (MATLAB, MERN stack)
- Management consulting (tech advisory for financial services)
- Stakeholder management
- Lean six sigma tools (Green belt)

WORK EXPERIENCE

MANAGEMENT CONSULTANT | SYNPULSE MANAGEMENT CONSULTING

Feb 2021 – Present | Sydney, NSW

Forensic Actuary for a Life Insurer in Australia

- Managing BAU tasks including setting and tracking KPIs for a team of 7
- Handling life insurance (income protection) claims for both retail and group claims
- Conducting data analysis and individual claims reconstruction and reported findings to stakeholders

Strategic Advisory for a Mid-tier Bank in APAC

- Designed process maps and a new target operating model for 5 business units
- Led meetings with bank's leadership team to provide guidance for decision making
- Evaluated of system bottlenecks and gathering key requirements
- Conducted market research to assess trends and determine best practices
- Gathered and documented key business requirements
- Conducted RFI and RFP evaluation for vendor evaluation and assessment

Corporate Social Responsibility Country Lead - Australia

- Organised an office wide carbon footprint challenge
- Organised a Christmas in August event to boost employee morale
- Organised a food drive for Foodbank NSW

PROCESS ENGINEER | COVER GENIUS

Mar 2020 - Jun 2020 | Sydney, NSW

Insurance Data Migration

 Conducted data analysis using tools such as Big Query, Power BI, Redash, Excel, SQL to identify areas for process improvement.

- Created technical documentation to navigate data migration from one platform to another
- Used project management tools such as Monday to prioritise and schedule tasks.

CONSULTANT & BUSINESS ANALYST | DXC TECHNOLOGY

Sep 2018 – Feb 2020 | Singapore

Retail banking project for a prominent bank

- Sole business analyst on the project, responsible for managing BAU tasks of development team
- Coordinated with internal and external stakeholders to gather key requirements
- Used project management tools to estimate project delivery timelines and plan resource allocation
- Created user stories using a AS-IS and TO-BE format
- Conducted unit testing and supported UAT efforts
- Created technical and functional specification documents

Data warehousing project for a defense/technology client

- Conducted data analysis using tools such as Informatica, SQL, Excel, Pivot Tables, SAP BW and VBA and identified limitations in the system
- Created technical documentation and functional specification documents
- Created process flow diagrams to help the team identify areas for improvement

LEAN SIX SIGMA PROJECT LEADER | AUBURN UNIVERSITY

Oct 2016 - May 2017 | Auburn, AL, USA

Lean six sigma-based process improvement for Golden Peanut and Tree Nut (manufacturing)

- Presented a proposal that improved inventory management system and optimised warehouse space, resulting in \$10 million cost savings.
- Conducted statistical analysis of raw data obtained from warehouse facility using Minitab, AutoCAD, Excel, MATLAB and used this data to generate recommendations for process improvement.
- Used lean six sigma tools such as VOC and 5S to identify customer needs, Kaizen to eliminate waste, DMAIC to plan project outline and process flow, Ishikawa (Fishbone) Diagram to conduct root cause analysis, Pareto, and Control Charts to set up a continuous improvement plan
- Conducted cost benefit analysis and rate of return analysis to determine the most cost-effective solution
- Proposed RFID (Radio Frequency Identification) and ASRS (Automated Storage and Retrieval System) technology
- Obtained competitive customised quotations from different suppliers and created new relationship opportunities for company